





Vijayaraj Krishnan

No: 2/8, kanniyappar Nayakar st, Allappakkam,

Porur, Chennai, 600 116

Phone: (+91) - 9884245756

Email: Vijayaraj2002@yahoo.com

Objective

Seeking a challenging opportunity in an organization where I can make optimum use of my knowledge and experience, which would enable me to improve my skills and strengths and also to the growth of the organization

Professional Summary

Have 16+ Years of total experience in IT infrastructure, IT infrastructure strategy, design, and services, Public and Private as a service infrastructure services (cloud), Server architecture, audit and compliance, Cloud Services, Data Center Operations, ITIL, Data Center Design, Remote Infrastructure Management, site in charge, Played different roles in the IT Infrastructure support. Staring from field support engineer to Datacenter Manager, System Administrator and Cloud Engineer etc., VMware (VCP 5.5), Linux with Microsoft Certified Professional.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

1. Trigyn Technology
Working at UN (UNAMID)

November 2011 to till date

- Cloud Engineer with VMware Administrator, Configuration management, Continuous Integration, Continuous Deployment and Cloud Implementation.
- Back-up | managing and monitoring backup in physical and cloud environment.
- Hands on experience in AZURE development, Worked on AZURE web application, app service, AZURE storage, Virtual Machines, fabric Controller, Azure AD, Azure search and Notification hub.
- Designed, configured and deployed Microsoft AZURE for a multitude applications
 Utilizing the Azure stack (Including Compute and Web, Mobile and Blobs, Resource
 Group, Azure SQL, cloud Services) Focusing on high availability, Fault tolerance,
 and auto-scaling.
- Expertise in Microsoft Azure cloud Service (PaaS & IaaS), Application insights, Document DB, Azure Monitoring, Key vault.,
- Developed methodologies for cloud migration, implemented best practice and helped to develop backup and recovery technics for application database on virtualization platform.
- Expensive involvement in Designing AZURE Resource Manager Template and in a designing custom build steps using PowerShell.
- Designed and developed cloud service projects and deployed to Web Apps

- PaaS and IaaS.
- Good at Manage Hosting plans for Azure Infrasture, Implementing & deploying workload
- On Virtual machines (VMs).
- Experience in migrating the existing V1(classic) Azure Infrasture into V2(ARM),
- Scripting and templating the whole end to end process as much as possible so that it is
- Customizable for each area migrated.
- Design, Plan and migrate deployments of customer On-promise data center/application to Microsoft Azure.
- Involved with planning designing and transforming envoirments from On-promises to cloud based.
- Work as Cloud Administrator on Microsoft Azure, involved in configuring Virtual machines, Resource groups, Storage account.

Projects

- Storage migration Eva 4400 to HP 3par storage.
- New C7000 Enclosure updating from flex 10 to flex fabric FCOE.
- Hp gen6 to Gen 7 and gen 9 migrated successfully.
- vSphere migration 5.5 to 6.0, 6.5,6.7 successfully.
- P2V migrations projects for Datacenter virtualization.
- Storage Consolidation Project.
- Virtual servers' application, database server, file servers migrated to AZURE.
- Leading a team of 3 VMware L2administrators.

2. IBM India Private Limited

March 2011 to September 2011

ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES

- Providing end to end support for an US based pharmaceutical client.
- Installation, configuration and troubleshooting of VMware 4.1, 4.0 and 3.5 Core OS
- Working for VMware projects Commissioning and Decommissioning the servers
- Provides support for Incident Management tickets
- Hardware vendor co-ordination (Dell and IBM) for hardware failures/replacements.
- Installing ESX Servers Patch and vCenters patching through Patch Management and health check Remediation in 26+ servers every 3 months.
- Managing Version of VMware ESX servers 2.1, 3.0, 3.5 and 4.1 through VCenter Server
- Profile Creating and Management. Data Store Creation and VMFS System Creation.
- VM Environment using IBM Storage and Net APP.
- VM Guest servers Performance Monitoring.
- Have Knowledge on New server deployments, ESX and VSphere Configuration, P2V,V2V,
 V-Motion

Knowledge Transition

Worked on knowledge transition starting from due diligence phase

- Worked with Architects on shadow and parallel phase on migration, design and Implementation
- Preparation of Process and work instruction document.

3. Aditya Birla Money Limited

Role: System Administrator Feb 2008 to Mar 2011

ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES

- VMware ESX Server and VCenter Server maintenance
- Creating Cluster and HA, DRS Configuration.
- P2V Conversion as per request for Management.
- VM Guest Server weekly backup from V-Ranger pro Tool.
- Create LUN's the SAN Storage (DS4800 and DS4300)
- Trading Application Support BSE, NSE, MCX and NCDEX (TCS, Acian Cerc and OMNESYS)
- Linux Proxy Server Maintenance & Linux Postfix mail Server Maintenance (Netcore)
- Provide Windows support and Trading Application support to 300 staff members in the corporate office.
- Administration of Symantec Anti-virus Server & monitoring the clients for automatic update on anti-virus definitions from the server.
- Configuring the Microsoft Outlook and Outlook Express for all the users to access mails.
- Configuring and Maintaining Domains, DNS, WINS, DHCP, File And Print and other Core Services.
- Fault tolerance in terms of RAID (hardware/software) configuring, taking backups using Windows Backup.

4. Cyber Software Systems Pvt Ltd,

(April 2006 - Feb 2008)

System Administrator

Managing the IT infrastructure-System, Network , Syorage etc

Roles and Responsibilities:

Prior Experience:

- Worked as Senior Technical Support Engineer @ Maha Electronics PVT Ltd, T.Nagar Chennai. NSP HP SERVICE PARTNER. Premium HP service partner. (2004 June 2006April)
- Worked as Customer Support Engineer @ Alfa computers, Kodambakkam, Chennai. Dealing with Computers and IT Peripherals. (2002-2004).

Education Qualifications

➤ **Diploma in Computer Technology** - Directorate of Technical Education Tamil Nadu - Thiru Seven Hills Polytechnics with 71% Aggregate. (1999-2000).

TECHNICAL CERTIFICATIONS

- VCP 5.5 Candidate ID: VMW-01339517Y-00469494
- Microsoft Certified Professional (MCP)
- > Completed CCNA AT SANSBOND NETWORKING SCHOOL, RANGARAJAPURAM
- Completed MCSA AT RJP INFOTEC KODAMBAKKAM.
- Successfully Completed Hewlett Packard Engineer Certifications for the following, Hewlett Packard Evo Service Engineer --certification on SMB Personal computing

PERSONAL DETAILS

• Fathers Name : Krishnan

• Nationality : Indian

Marital Status : Married

• Languages Known : Tamil, English, Telugu

• Passport Number : Z4212056

Place: Chennai

Date: Vijayaraj Krishnan